<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">

<!-- Material initially from RFC 3552           Security Considerations Guidelines          July 2003 -->
<H3>Security and Privacy Considerations</H3>
<p>
   While it is not a requirement that any given protocol or system be
   immune to all forms of attack, it is still necessary for authors to
   consider as many forms as possible.  Part of the purpose of the
   Security Considerations section is to explain what attacks are out of
   scope and what countermeasures can be applied to defend against them.
   In
</p><p>
   There should be a clear description of the kinds of threats on the
   described protocol or technology.  This should be approached as an
   effort to perform "due diligence" in describing all known or
   foreseeable risks and threats to potential implementers and users.
</p><p>
   Authors MUST describe
</p><p>

      1.   which attacks are out of scope (and why!)
</p><p>
      2.   which attacks are in-scope
</p><p>
      2.1  and the protocol is susceptible to
</p><p>
      2.2  and the protocol protects against
</p><p>

   At least the following forms of attack MUST be considered:
   eavesdropping, replay, message insertion, deletion, modification, and
   man-in-the-middle.  Potential denial of service attacks MUST be
   identified as well.  If the protocol incorporates cryptographic
   protection mechanisms, it should be clearly indicated which portions
   of the data are protected and what the protections are (i.e.,
   integrity only, confidentiality, and/or endpoint authentication,
   etc.).  Some indication should also be given to what sorts of attacks
   the cryptographic protection is susceptible.  Data which should be
   held secret (keying material, random seeds, etc.) should be clearly
   labeled.
</p><p>

   If the technology involves authentication, particularly user-host
   authentication, the security of the authentication method MUST be
   clearly specified.  That is, authors MUST document the assumptions
   that the security of this authentication method is predicated upon.
   For instance, in the case of the UNIX username/password login method,
   a statement to the effect of:
</p><p>

      Authentication in the system is secure only to the extent that it
      is difficult to guess or obtain a ASCII password that is a maximum
      of 8 characters long.  These passwords can be obtained by sniffing
      telnet sessions or by running the 'crack' program using the
      contents of the /etc/passwd file.  Attempts to protect against
      on-line password guessing by (1) disconnecting after several
      unsuccessful login attempts and (2) waiting between successive
      password prompts is effective only to the extent that attackers
      are impatient.
</p><p>

      Because the /etc/passwd file maps usernames to user ids, groups,
      etc. it must be world readable.  In order to permit this usage but
      make running crack more difficult, the file is often split into
      /etc/passwd and a 'shadow' password file.  The shadow file is not
      world readable and contains the encrypted password.  The regular
      /etc/passwd file contains a dummy password in its place.
</p><p>

   It is insufficient to simply state that one's protocol should be run
   over some lower layer security protocol.  If a system relies upon
   lower layer security services for security, the protections those
   services are expected to provide MUST be clearly specified.  In
   addition, the resultant properties of the combined system need to be
   specified.
</p><p>

   Note: In general, the IESG will not approve standards track protocols
   which do not provide for strong authentication, either internal to
   the protocol or through tight binding to a lower layer security
   protocol.
</p><p>

   The threat environment addressed by the Security Considerations
   section MUST at a minimum include deployment across the global
   Internet across multiple administrative boundaries without assuming
   that firewalls are in place, even if only to provide justification
   for why such consideration is out of scope for the protocol.  It is
   not acceptable to only discuss threats applicable to LANs and ignore
   the broader threat environment.  All IETF standards-track protocols
   are considered likely to have deployment in the global Internet.  In
   some cases, there might be an Applicability Statement discouraging
   use of a technology or protocol in a particular environment.
   Nonetheless, the security issues of broader deployment should be
   discussed in the document.
</p><p>

   There should be a clear description of the residual risk to the user
   or operator of that protocol after threat mitigation has been
   deployed.  Such risks might arise from compromise in a related
   protocol (e.g., IPsec is useless if key management has been
   compromised), from incorrect implementation, compromise of the
   security technology used for risk reduction (e.g., a cipher with a
   40-bit key), or there might be risks that are not addressed by the
   protocol specification (e.g., denial of service attacks on an
   underlying link protocol).  Particular care should be taken in
   situations where the compromise of a single system would compromise
   an entire protocol.  For instance, in general protocol designers
   assume that end-systems are inviolate and don't worry about physical
   attack.  However, in cases (such as a certificate authority) where
   compromise of a single system could lead to widespread compromises,
   it is appropriate to consider systems and physical security as well.
</p><p>

   There should also be some discussion of potential security risks
   arising from potential misapplications of the protocol or technology
   described in the RFC.  This might be coupled with an Applicability
   Statement for that RFC.
  </p>
</div>